mpex.com 2019-01-09

# Midwest Photo Privacy Policy

## Privacy Policy Overview

At Midwest Photo (the "Company") we take your privacy seriously. This Privacy Policy governs our "Websites" including mpex.com, mpexrentals.com, mpex-experience.com, mpexlearningstudio.com, prints.mpex.com, mobile sites, email communications and any other related services. This policy (the “Privacy Policy”) was created to inform you of the type of information the Company will collect from you and how the Company will use it and your choices about it. We only use that information where we have a proper legal basis for doing so.

By visiting or using any of our services, you consent to be bound by the terms of this Privacy Policy and our terms of use and that you may be transferring your data to, and consent to having your data transferred to and processed in the United States.

 **Please note:** you are not obligated by law to provide us with any information. You hereby acknowledge, warrant and agree that any information you do provide us is provided of your own free will and consent, for the purposes and uses described herein.

## What Information is collected?

The information that we learn from users helps us personalize and continue to improve our services and your experience with us.

 **Information You Provide to Us:** We may receive and store information you enter on our website or provide to us in anyway. This may include:

  * Your name
  * E-mail
  * Mailing address
  * Phone number
  * Birthdate (optional)
  * Country in which you live
  * Any other information you provide when placing an order with us while registering for a customer account with us, entering a contest or sweepstakes, providing feedback to us, filling out a survey, sending messages via our online chat or requesting information or assistance from us.

There is also information that may be automatically collected including (but not exclusive to) your information that your browser or mobile application automatically sends, "cookies," IP address, profile information, preferences, operating system, browser or mobile application type and settings, computer specifications, and activity on our websites.

If you buy something on our Websites or make any payment, we may collect payment information, contact information (address and phone number), delivery details and details of what you bought, and any other information required to enable you to access and use the payment services. This information will be used, among other things, by our third-party payment processer to:

  * Process and fulfill your order via Third Party Services (as defined below) such as PayPal, FuturePay, Amazon Pay, shipping companies or others.
  * Detect and prevent fraud, abuse, security incidents, and other harmful activity.
  * Conduct security investigations and risk assessments.
  * Comply with legal obligations.
  * Enforce the payment terms and other payment policies.
  * With your consent, send you promotional messages, marketing, advertising, and other information that may be of interest to you based on your selected preferences.

The Third-Party Services processes this information given its legitimate interest in improving the payment services and its users’ experience with it, and where it is necessary for the adequate performance of the contract with you and to comply with applicable laws.

We may also receive information about you and your activity outside our websites in connection with us from our affiliates, advertisers, partners, vendors and other third parties we work with, or other publicly available sources.

It is important to understand that you have no legal obligation to share any information with Midwest Photo and you hereby agree and acknowledge that are you doing so willingly and voluntarily. You hereby also agree and acknowledge that we may store information in databases which will be kept and operate in accordance with all applicable laws and regulations. We will not collect any information from you without your consent, which is obtained, through your acceptance of our Terms & Conditions and this Privacy Policy.

## What is your information used for?

We may collect any of the information we receive from you, subject to applicable law. Further, any of the information that may be collected, may be used to:

  * Personalize your experience with the Company.
  * Improve your experience on our Websites.
  * Improve customer service and provide technical assistance.
  * Practical considerations such as, but not limited to, sending order and shipping confirmations, processing your transactions (if applicable).
  * Administer contests, promotions, surveys or other site features.
  * Email Communication (information and updates including Company news, updates, related product or service information). If you no longer wish to receive promotional emails from us, please unsubscribe, change your profile settings within your customer account or contact us to remove your information. Please note we will continue to send any transactional emails regarding purchase transactions, order tracking, etc.
  * Sales related communications (personal emails and phone calls, event invitations etc.).

We may contact you with important information regarding our services, or your use thereof, such as notices (through any of the means available to us) if a certain service is temporarily suspended for maintenance, reply to your e-mail, notify you of changes in our services. You may not be able to opt-out of receiving some of such shipping and order related messages.

## Our website security measures

You can access your personal information on our Website through a username and password that you create. This password is encrypted, and we recommend that you do not share it with anyone. We also encourage you to set a strong password for your account.

All Websites operated by Midwest Photo offer HTTPS secure access to most areas on our Websites, i.e. the transmission of sensitive payment information (such as a credit card number) through our designated purchase forms is protected by an SSL encrypted connection. Please understand that, despite our best efforts, no security measures are completely fool-proof. We also regularly monitor our systems for possible vulnerabilities and attacks, and regularly seek new ways for enhancing the security of our services and protection of our users’ privacy. Furthermore, because certain areas on our Websites might be less secure than others, and since e-mail and instant messaging are not recognized as secure forms of communications, we request and encourage you not to share any personal information on any of these areas or via any of these methods.

## Do these websites use cookies?

Yes, we may now or in the future use cookies without further notice. Cookies are small files that a site or its service provider transfers to your computer’s hard drive through your web browser (if you allow) that enable the site’s or service provider’s systems to recognize your browser and capture and remember certain information. You may change this setting in your browser, so your browser may either refuse all cookies or informs you when a cookie is being sent.

We use cookies to understand and save your preferences and log in Information for future visits and to compile general data about site traffic and site interaction so that we can offer better experiences, including the ability to improve the Website navigation and present you with information that is more relevant to your needs. The Company may contract with a third-party service provider to assist in better understanding the Website’s visitors. These service providers are not permitted to use the Information collected on the Website except to help the Company conduct and improve business and interaction with you.

We use Google Analytics to help us understand how our customers use the Websites. You can read more about how Google uses your Personal Information [here](https://www.google.com/intl/en/policies/privacy/).

You can also opt-out of Google Analytics [here](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout).

We may also share your personal information to comply with applicable laws and regulations, to respond to a subpoena, search warrant or other lawful requests for information we receive, or to otherwise protect our rights.

We may embed content from other sites such as YouTube (videos) and social media sites such as Facebook, LinkedIn and Twitter. We have no control over whether embedded content sets a cookie on your browser or not.

## Is any Information disclosed to outside parties?

The Company does not sell, trade, or otherwise transfer to outside parties your personal information. This does not include affiliated entities controlled by us or trusted third parties who assist the Company in operating the Website, conducting the Company’s business, or servicing you, or third-party vendors or service providers (including third parties that are located in countries other than your own), so long as those parties agree to keep this information confidential. If you buy something via the Website, we may share information required to process the transaction and for the fulfillment of your order, including by third parties and subject to such third parties’ policies.

We may share information with selected service providers, whose services and solutions complement, facilitate and enhance our own. These include hosting and server co-location services, communications and content delivery networks (CDNs), data and cyber security services, billing and payment processing services, domain name registrars, fraud detection and prevention services, web analytics, e-mail distribution and monitoring services, session recording and remote access services, performance measurement data optimization and marketing services, content providers, and our legal and financial advisors (collectively, “Third Party Service(s)”). Such Third-Party Services may receive or otherwise have access to our users Information, in its entirety or in part – depending on each of their roles and purposes in facilitating and enhancing our services and business and may only use it for such purposes. We are not responsible for such websites’ or services’ privacy practices and encourage you to be aware when you leave our services and read the privacy statements of each website and service you visit. This Privacy Policy does not apply to such linked third-party websites and services.

If you upload any user content to the Website, platform and/or provide it in any other way as part of the use of any service, you do so at your own risk.

We cannot control the actions of other users or members of the public who may access your content and are not responsible for the circumvention of any privacy settings or security measures you or we may have placed on your content or information (including, for instance, password-protected areas). You understand and acknowledge that, even after its removal by you or us, copies of content may remain viewable in cached and archived pages or if any third parties have copied or stored such content.

## Third Party Website Links

The Company Website may contain links to or features from other websites, applications, services etc. (for example: YouTube, Facebook, Instagram). This Privacy Policy covers only the policies of this Company and not of any other websites, applications or services. The Company is not responsible for the privacy policies of third parties. If you choose to link to a third-party website, application or service you should be sure to read the privacy policy of that specific website, application or service.

## Children’s Privacy

The Company’s products and Website services are targeted for a general audience and not for children under the age of 13. To the best of the Company’s ability, it will not collect Information from children under the age of 13. If the Company becomes aware of such information, it will do its best to remove it as soon as possible.

## EU GDPR Compliance

We are doing our best to make sure that an EU citizen's personal information collected by us shall be in compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR). Among other things, if you’re an EU user, you can:

  * You may access, correct, update or request deletion of your personal information at any time by contacting us using the contact details provided in the 'Contact Us' section of this privacy policy. Please note, you can update your information anytime within your customer account settings. If you have problems updating the information or if you would like us to delete it, contact us at the information provided.
  * Object to us collecting or processing your information. You can ask us to stop using your information, including when we use your information to send you marketing emails. If you opt out of receiving marketing messages from us, we may still send you updates about your account and order information. We only send you marketing material if you’ve agreed to it, but if you’d rather we don’t, you can easily unsubscribe at any time through the easy-to-find link at the bottom of all email communication.
  * In some jurisdictions, applicable law may entitle you to request copies of your personal information held by us.
  * To exercise any of these rights, please contact us in accordance with the contact details set forth in this policy. Please note that if you are not subject to EU law, these rights do not apply.

## Retention of Information

When you place an order through the Websites, we will maintain your order information for our records unless and until you ask us to delete this information.

  * We may retain some information as necessary for our legitimate business interests, such as fraud detection and prevention and enhancing safety.
  * We may retain and use Information to the extent necessary to comply with our legal obligations (such as tax, legal reporting and auditing obligations).
  * Information you have shared with others may continue to be publicly visible, even after your account is deactivated. However, attribution of such information to you will be removed. Additionally, some copies of your information (e.g., log records) may remain in our database.
  * Because we maintain the platform to protect from accidental or malicious loss and destruction, residual copies of your information may not be removed from our backup systems for a limited period of time.

## Terms and Conditions

Please also visit the [Terms and Conditions](https://mpex.com/terms-and-conditions/) section of our websites for establishing the use, disclaimers, and limitations of liability governing the use of our Website, platform, applications and services.

## Your Consent

**By using any of our Websites, platform and/or our services you consent to the online Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this policy please do not use the platform or services or purchase products from, or otherwise use the Websites and please avoid providing the Company with your information.**

There will be certain circumstances in which you will be given the choice to opt-in or opt-out of having your personal information used (for example choosing whether or not you want to receive information on similar products when you place an order).

Where you have provided your consent to the collection and/or processing of your information by us you may withdraw your consent at any time by sending a communication to the Company specifying which consent you are withdrawing. Please note that the withdrawal of your consent does not affect the lawfulness of any processing activities based on such consent before its withdrawal.

## Your choices

Our goal is to give you simple choices regarding your information. If you have an account, many of the choices you have are built directly into the Website, platform or your settings. Please note that we may ask you to verify your identity before taking further action on your request. We will make reasonable efforts to respond to your request in a reasonable time and subject to any applicable law. For example, you can:

  * Request information regarding your personal Information collected by us and its storage.
  * Edit information in your account or profile.
  * Link or unlink your account from other services (like Facebook, Google, Instagram or Twitter).
  * Close your account at any time. When you close your account, we’ll deactivate it and remove your content from display (subject to backup and retention requirements).

You also have choices available to you through the device or software you use to access us. For example:

  * The browser you use lets you control cookies or other types of local data storage.
  * Your mobile device lets you choose how and whether your location, photos, advertising identifiers and other data is shared with us.

To learn more about these choices, please see the information provided by your device or software provider.

## Changes to Privacy Policy

If the Company decides to change the Privacy Policy, the changes will be posted on this page, we will provide notices on the Website and in any other manner required, and/or update the Privacy Policy modification date above. If you continue to use our services after those changes are in effect, you agree to the new policy. If the changes are significant, we may provide a more prominent notice or get your consent, as required by law.

## Contact us

For further questions or requests (including requests to receive a copy of any personal information that the Company holds about you) regarding this Privacy Policy you may contact us using the information below:

  * By email: [privacy@mpex.com](mailto:privacy@mpex.com)
  * By telephone at: [1-866-940-3686](tel:18669403686)
  * By sending a letter to  
Midwest Photo  
(Attention: Ken Lewis)  
2887 Silver Dr.  
Columbus, Oh 43211
